Santiago Arellano

+1 (425) 221-5453 santy.arellano039@gmail.com https://ssam.dev

Summary

I'm a Backend Engineer at Microsoft with 3 years of experience, including internships at Microsoft, Twitter, and Oracle. With a Bachelor's in Computer Science, I specialize in Rust, C#, and C/C++. My passion lies in game development, where I've published games, won game jam awards, and created my own game engine and framework. Looking to apply my skills in graphics, engine, or gameplay engineering in creating immersive gaming experiences.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Rust, C#, C/C++, SQL. Game Engine patterns: ECS, POO, Observers, Prototypes, Spacial partitions, etc. Graphics: OpenGL, WGPU, SDL.

EXPERIENCE

Microsoft, Redmond — Software Engineer

October 2023 - PRESENT

- Work on custom access proxies for the Global Secure Access service, focusing on encryption, networking, and performance using C# and Rust.
- Led the upgrade of encryption tooling and processes, ensuring safe rollouts capable of handling millions of requests per minute.
- Actively participated in on-call rotation and collaborated with cross-functional teams to develop new features and improve interfaces.

Twitter, Remote — 2 Software Engineering Internships

2021 - 2022

- Worked on the chats platform team, implementing features like the scroll-to-bottom button and conversation pinning. Improved tweet display within conversations, primarily using Kotlin, Java, and XML
- Worked on the Notifications team, integrating a sensor & ML framework to improve user interaction.

Oracle, Remote — Software Engineering Internship

Jun 2021 - Mar 2022

• Developed tests for a new product, utilizing Python scripting, C, and SQL to create and execute test cases.

EDUCATION

ITESM, Mexico — Bachelor's in Computer Science

Aug 2017 - June 2023

AWARDS

Best Game at Global Game Jam sponsored by TLM.

Lord of the Code MX 1st place out of 100 participants nationwide (competitive programming).